What should we do…?
该怎么办呢？
What do you think, sir?
大人打算怎么办？
THIS STORY IS A FICION, AND ALL NAMES OF FIGURES ND ORGANIZATIONS ARE FICTITIOUS.
（本作所有人物、组织名均为虚构）
MOREOVER, THE STORY HAS NO RELATION TO REAL-LIFE INCIDENTS AND EVENTS.
（与任何特定事件或现象无关）
After the execution
风明被处刑之后
of Fengming, her relatives were robbed of their wealth,
风明亲属的财产全数充公
and were sentenced to varying degrees of corporal punishment.
并且都被处以或轻或重的肉刑
The crime was said to be committed by Fengming alone,
这件事被认为是风明的独断独行
and it was fortunate that her master, Ah-Duo, was not questioned.
幸好她的主子阿多妃未受牵累
And now,
而现在
I have the names from Fengming's family and anyone with connections to the family.
这儿有一份 风明老家和所有相关人士的名簿
The list contains names of the customers who conducted business with the family.
名簿中也有生意往来的客户
They did a wide variety of business, not just beekeeping.
看来除了养蜂之外 生意范围也相当广泛
There are about 80 people with connections
后宫内相关人士的女儿
in the rear palace.
大约有八十人
Eighty people out of 2,000, huh?
两千人中就有八十人？
That's quite a blow.
命中率相当高啊
JADE PAVILION: MAOMAO
（翡翠宫 猫猫）
The party where the Apothecary was sold off to after being kidnapped
药师被掳走后 买下她的买主
had connections to the family.
似乎也是相关人士之一
We can cover this up if you'd like.
如果您想要的话 可以隐蔽这件事
"If you'd like."
“如果我想要的话”
Of course, what else?
说的也是
It doesn't matter if it's right or wrong.
无关是非对错
Whatever I say will happen.
只要我开口 事情就会这么办
She's clear about the divide between commoners and nobility.
平民和贵族的划分在于
She'll follow whatever order is given to her.
无论是何等令人厌恶的命令 平民都得接受吧
It's simple for me to strike down any order.
要下命令很简单
I can just decide right now.
要是能轻易决定就好了
If I cover this up, I can keep her in the rear palace.
隐蔽这件事的话 就能将她留在后宫
But what if that's not what she wants?
但如果她的心意并非如此
If she learned she was forced to remain where she didn't want to be,
要是她发现自己 被强留在并不喜欢的地方时
how would she react?
会有何反应呢？
I'm afraid of deepening the gap
我们之间的界线
that already exists between us.
恐怕会变成更大的鸿沟吧
Sir Jinshi.
壬氏大人
I thought she was just a convenient chess piece.
您不是说她是个好用的棋子吗？
-A mass firing? -Yeah, that's right.
-集体解雇？ -对啊
All the daughters of parents that did business
听说和那个家族 有过生意往来的人家女儿
with that family have to quit.
全部都要被辞退
It's going to be a large number of girls.
人数好像相当多哦
I see…
是哦…
There's a lot of girls who are panicking because they have to quit suddenly.
我身边也有 因为突然被解雇而烦恼的人
Looks like that family did business with a lot of people.
那个家族一定和很多人做生意吧
I have a bad feeling about this.
怎么有种不好的预感？
I'd be in a bind if I was fired right now.
要是现在被解雇会很麻烦的
The timing is bad.
时间点很不妙
After Lihaku's visit,
在李白之后
I haven't been able to send any wealthy customers to Grams.
还没能介绍任何贵客给老鸨
If I go back now…
如果现在回去的话…
I'm home!
我回来了
Here's a customer!
这是你的客人！
I'll definitely be sold off…
一定会被卖掉的
Maomao?
猫猫？
When I checked last time, my registered family was
之前确认的时候 我在文书上登记的老家
listed as a merchant family that conducts trade.
是个做买卖的商家
If Fengming's family are bee farmers,
如果风明的老家是养蜂人家
they may have some kind of
两边在生意上
connection!
也许有过接触也不一定
Sir Jinshi!
壬氏大人
What's wrong? You're out of breath.
真难得 你怎么喘成这样？
-Well… -Calm down. Your face is all red.
-那个… -冷静点 你的脸都涨红了
I need to talk to you.
我有话想跟您说
Fine. Let's talk inside.
我知道了 到屋里说吧
It's about the mass firing, right?
是关于集体解雇的事 对吧？
Yes.
对
-What'll happen to me? -Here's the registry.
-我会受到什么样的处置？ -名簿在这儿
So I'll be fired?
也就是说 我被解雇了？
What do you want?
你想怎么做？
I thought she was just a convenient chess piece.
您不是说她是个好用的棋子吗？
Ever since I became Lady Gyokuyou's attendant,
自从我成了玉叶娘娘的侍女之后
I can taste test, and have access to the medical office.
我能试毒 也能进出太医院
I enjoy the life I have now.
我很喜欢现在的生活
But I'm just a palace woman.
但我只是一介宫女
I'm in no position to request not to be fired.
并没有立场请求不被解雇
I can't look like I'm begging…
不能露出乞怜的神情…
I'm just a palace woman.
我只是名宫女
Whether it's menial work, cooking, or taste testing,
只要大人吩咐 不论是杂工
I'll do whatever you say, if it's an order.
厨娘或试毒人 我都会照做
"If it's an order…"
“只要大人吩咐…”
That's right.
没错
As long as it's an order, I can get through this.
只要被命令的话 我就会尽力完成职责
I won't complain even if my salary goes down.
纵使薪俸减少一点 我也没有怨言
If I can buy some time before I'm sold off, I can survive.
只要能在卖身前争取到一些时间 总有办法脱困的
So, don't fire me!
所以 请不要解雇我
I understand.
我明白了
So…
那么…
I'll pay as much as I can.
我会多给点补偿的
-Oh… -Negotiation failed.
-咦… -交涉失败
Maomao has been fired.
猫猫 解雇
All right, then.
好了
How long are you going to stay like that?
您要这个样子到什么时候？
You should have stopped her.
果然当初该挽留她比较好吧？
Don't say anything.
什么都别说了
The week after she was dismissed,
收到解雇通知后隔周
Xiaomao returned to the pleasure district.
小猫就回花街去了
I hear she was courteous
听说她礼数周到
and said goodbye to all the people that took care of her.
照顾过她的地方都逐一打了招呼
I won't help you even if you regret this.
你要是后悔我可不管哦
He lost his favorite toy.
这个人弄丢了喜欢的玩具时
It'll be a lot of work to find an interesting replacement toy for him.
可是费尽了一番功夫 才找到珍奇的玩具来代替
I want the other one!
我只想要那个啦！
No…
不对…
Perhaps that girl isn't a toy after all.
也许不应该 把那个姑娘跟玩具相提并论吧
He didn't make her stay because he didn't want to use her.
就是因为不想当成工具利用 所以才放弃挽留她
What a burdensome master I have. He's a lot of work.
真是麻烦又费事的主子啊
If I can't find a replacement…
替代品行不通的话…
Perhaps I'll ask that soldier.
去找那位武官问看看吧
Depressed, sulking, gloomy…
消沉、懊恼、阴郁…
See. You look better without freckles!
果然 没有雀斑漂亮多了
I'll lend you my lipstick.
我的唇脂借你吧
I never imagined that I would ever get ready for a banquet with Maomao…
没想到会有和猫猫一起赴宴的一天呢
Our work tonight is
今晚的工作
a banquet for the nobility held outside of the brothel.
是在青楼外参加某位贵人的宴会
It costs that much money to invite courtesans to one's mansion.
光是把要娼妓叫到宅邸就所费不赀
Not only that,
不只如此
one night of entertainment costs a year's worth of salary for a common man.
陪酒一晚就得花掉平民一年银两
To call the Three Princesses of the Verdigris House at the same time…
绿青馆的三姬 也一口气叫了过去
Some people are just really rich, huh?
有钱人还真的是很有钱
I might be going with you,
虽然说是一起去
but I'll just be there to support you, Big Sisters.
但我只是衬托大姐们的角色而已
Here you go, Maomao.
来吧 猫猫
I was able to get more money than I imagined when I left the rear palace.
因为离开后宫时 拿到了比想象还要丰厚的钱财
That's why I was able to prevent being sold off.
总之算是摆脱了卖身的命运
A supporting role is very important.
即使是陪衬 也是重要的工作
Let's work hard, Maomao!
猫猫 拜托你咯
You're really cute!
这不是很可爱嘛
It's almost time! Hurry up…
时间差不多了 动作快点
Hey, you look better than usual.
哦 稍微变得漂亮了点呢
I can get you a customer right now, if you'd like.
你想要的话 现在就接客也可以哦
Looks like Grams really wants me to be a courtesan.
老鸨真的是用尽办法想让我当娼妓呢
Go earn us some money!
去大赚一笔吧！
I can't sing poetry, and I can't play erhu.
我不会吟诗咏歌 也不会拉二胡
Never mind dancing.
更别说是跳舞了
I'm just an apothecary's daughter who's only interested in medicine.
我明明是个除了药之外 全都不感兴趣的药师女儿
But she keeps approaching me with offers these past few years…
但这几年来 她的行为更是明显
As expected of nobility.
真不愧是富贵人家
This house is packed with super-expensive furnishings!
到处都是让人眼花撩乱的家具
I'm sure they won't notice if I take one…
顺手拿个纪念品回去 也不会被发现吧…
No, I shouldn't.
不 这可不行
It's this room right here.
请往这个房间
I hear they're high court officials who are friends of Lihaku's.
听说是李白大人介绍的宫廷高官
But they're younger than I imagined.
但比想象中的年轻呢
Drool…
流口水了…
All right, let's go.
好 走吧
If he knew someone this rich,
既然有这么多有钱朋友
he should've introduced me earlier!
要是早点介绍给我就好了
If they're Lihaku's connections,
因为是李白大人的相识
then some of my debt might've been taken away.
债款也许会稍微减少一点吧
All right, I have to work.
好吧 该工作了
I know it's work, but it's tiring to smile all the time.
虽然说是工作 但要一直笑还真是累人
Oh? Isn't he entertained?
咦？是觉得无聊吗？
Excuse me.
打扰了
Leave me alone.
别管我
I want to be alone.
我想一个人待着
Huh? His voice sounds familiar…
咦？这声音好像在哪儿听过…
Sir Jinshi?
壬氏大人？
Why are you running away?
为什么要躲？
You can't touch courtesans. Don't you know?
请不要碰娼妓
Has anyone ever told you that you look really different with makeup?
有人说过你化妆后判若两人吗？
I get that a lot.
常有人这么说
Why are you dressed like that?
话说 这身打扮是怎么回事？
I'm earning money.
我正在做短工
-At a brothel? -Yes.
-青楼的？ -对
Could it be, you…?
你难道…
He must be in the habit of questioning people's chastity.
这人好像有 喜欢怀疑别人贞洁的性格呢
I don't take any personal customers.
我并没有单独接客哦
-Yet. -Yet…
-还没有 -还没有…
Shall I buy you, then?
那我买下你吧？
What? You've got to be kidding…
什么？您说笑…
Wait, that might be a good idea.
说不定不错呢
It won't be so bad to work in the rear palace again.
再回去后宫工作也不错
I thought you quit because you didn't like it there.
你不是讨厌那儿才辞职的吗？
What? When did I say that?
什么？我什么时候说过那种话了？
I said I wanted to keep working there. You're the one that fired me.
我本来想留下来的 但将我解雇的不是您吗？
What?
什么？
Yes, it was annoying work,
虽然的确有很多麻烦事
but not anyone can become a food taster.
但试毒人也并非是想当就能当上的
My only complaint was I couldn't experiment with my poisons.
硬要挑毛病的话 就是不能做毒物实验罢了
You shouldn't experiment with poison.
毒物实验还是别做了吧
His expressions are really childish today…
今天的表情感觉又更孩子气了…
That's right. That's the kind of person you are.
也是 你就是这种人啊
What do you mean?
什么意思？
Are you ever told that you don't explain yourself enough?
有人说过你讲话太简略吗？
I get that a lot.
常有人这么说
Why are you running from me?
所以说为什么要躲？
It's the rules.
规矩就是如此
-It's just a little. -It's against the rules.
-碰一下无妨吧？ -不行
-It won't cost you anything! -My willpower.
-又不会少块肉 -精力会减少的
Just one hand. Just the fingertips!
一只手就好 指尖行了吧
I forgot how stubborn this guy was…
对哦 都忘了这人有多死缠烂打…
Just the fingertips, okay?
只能用指尖哦
What…
呃…
This dude…
这家伙…
Now I'm blushing too!
会害我也脸红的！
Oh, when did that happen?
哎呀 什么时候开始的？
-You should've told us, Maomao! -So embarrassing.
-猫猫真是的 -真让人害羞呢
Hey, Big Sisters! Sir Gaoshun?
大姐！高顺大人？
I was in so much of a frenzy
在那之后 我头脑一片混乱
I don't really remember what happened after.
不太记得发生了什么事
-Who was that? -How do you know him?
-那个人是谁？ -你们是什么关系？
Geez. You're good!
真是的 太厉害了
I just remember that Big Sisters' interrogations were
只有大姐们纠缠不休地追问
never-ending…
记得很清楚
VERDIGRIS HOUSE
（绿青馆）
All right, next…
接下来…
I'll make some just in case.
为免万一 来做一些吧
Nothing good ever happens without my freckles.
没画上雀斑就净是发生坏事
That must've been last winter…
那已经是去年冬天的事了…
I was surprised to be kidnapped,
被掳走就已经很惊讶了
but to think I was sold off to the rear palace…
竟然还被卖到了后宫…
Not only that, I also got promoted to be an attendant.
不只如此 还被晋升为侍女
I was supposed to stay out of people's business until my term was up…
本来还想低调地待到卖身契结束呢
Maomao. Is it ready?
猫猫 做好了吗？
Yeah. Here it is.
嗯 好了
I need you to see a patient. Can you do it?
我想请你看个病人 能拜托你吗？
Okay.
知道了
The rear palace, huh?
后宫啊…
That's the one place I never wanted to get involved in…
真是一辈子都不想牵扯上的地方呢
I hope everyone's doing well.
不知道大家过得好吗？
I'm leaving now.
我要出来了
Stay put. You only have so many chances to bathe here.
待着吧 毕竟你难得有机会泡澡
So what are your plans now?
之后有什么打算？
I'll pay back my debt.
债款我会好好还清的
Of course you will.
那是当然的
Are you going back to the rear palace?
你打算回后宫吗？
I don't know.
我不知道
But maybe, the rear palace and the pleasure district…
但后宫和花街也许
Are not so different.
没有什么不同
I see.
是吗？
Can't sleep?
睡不着吗？
I'm going to get some fresh air.
我去外面透透气
-Be careful. -Yeah.
-小心点 -好
The rear palace, the pleasure district, it's all the same…
后宫还是花街 没有什么不同
It's a flower garden, and a bird's cage…
是花园 也是鸟笼…
LUOMEN
（罗门）
What will happen next?
接下来会怎么样呢？
So cold…
好冷
VERDIGRIS HOUSE
（绿青馆）
A few days later,
几天后
a beautiful nobleman comes to the capital's pleasure district.
京城的花街来了一位俊秀的贵人
Equipped with enough money to make even Grams happy,
那名男子带着让老鸨目眩的钱财
and, for some reason…
以及不知为何…
a strange plant growing out of an insect…
从昆虫身上长出的奇妙怪草
All this man wished for was one girl.
所求只为一名姑娘
PREVIEW OF NEXT EPISODE
（下集预告）
Next Episode, "Serving in the Outer Court."
下一集 《外廷勤务》
Subtitle translation by: Yukimi Ohashi
字幕翻译：欧德慧